就像旋风过度简化版的术语
That is like the whirlwind oversimplified
version of the terminology
与库伯内特联系的人
associated with Kubernetes.
我也在这里跳过很多事情
I am skipping a lot of
things here as well.
这里是一个悲伤的东西，在 Windows 系统里做这个
So here's the kind of the sad thing, doing
this within the Windows subsystem for
Linux 现在基本是不可能的。
Linux is basically impossible right now.
这不是 Windows 团队重点关注的事情，它即将来临。
It's not something that the Windows
team has focused on yet, it is coming.
所以别在 WSL 范围内尝试这样做。
So don't try and
do this within WSL at the moment.
或者你可以去查查看它是否已经被修复了
Or you can go look it up and
see if it's been fixed right now,
但今天，在 WSL 的时候，基本上是不可能的。
but today at this moment, with WSL,
it's basically impossible.
所以如果你和这里一起做这个
So if you're doing this alongside
with here in Windows, either to open
Ubuntu VM ，然后尝试这一过程，然后再去喝杯咖啡，然后享受旅程 [LAUGH]。
Ubuntu VM and try this or just grab
a coffee and enjoy the journey [LAUGH].
好了我们要和库伯内特做一个非常非常基本的互动
All right, so we're gonna do a very,
very basic interaction with Kubernetes.
我要给你看看我的 Docker
So I'm gonna show you up here,
where's my Docker?
我有我的 Docker 鲸在这里有个选项卡
So I have my Docker whale right there and
there is a tab here for
Kubernetes ，您可以切换上下文。
Kubernetes, and you can switch contexts.
我有两个上下文，所以您可能只需要一个 Docker Desktop。
I have two context and so you likely will
just have one which is Docker Desktop.
但还有一个叫 Minikube ，你也可以运行。
But there's another one called
Minikube that you can run as well.
如果您在 Linux 中，那么需要使用 Minikubbe，
If you're in Linux,
you'll need to use Minikube,
它就像库伯内特的控制结构
and it's basically like a control
structure for Kubernetes.
但我们会在 Mac OS 上为我们运行 Docker Desktop
But we're gonna have Docker Desktop
running for us on Mac OS so
请确保已完成此操作，然后我希望您启用本地集群。
make sure that it's done that and then
I want you to enable the local cluster.
如果尚未启用，
If it's not already enabled,
你们中的某些人可能已经启用了
some of you will probably
will have it already enabled.
你可以看到我有 Kubernetes 的开始
And you can see up here I have
Kubernetes is starting, and
然后我们就去我们的 Docker 桌面
then we're gonna go over
here to our Docker Desktop.
你可以看到我的提示其实已经证明了我在用
You can see here my prompt actually
already shows me that I'm using
Docker Desktop。
Docker Desktop.
但如果我把它换到这里来
But if I switched it to,
come back over here,
我可以换到 Minikube 就像那样如果我打了 Enter键
I could switch to Minikube just like that,
and if I hit Enter,
你会发现它会在这里切换到 Minikubbe
you'll see that it
switches here to Minikube.
让我们回到 Docker Desktop。
Let us go back to Docker Desktop.
好吧接下来我要你安装的是库贝控件
All right, so the next thing I need
you to install is kube control or
这取决于你怎么判断它的发音是什么
kube cuddle, it depends on who you ask
of how you pronounce it, which is this.
这显然意味着 kutbe 的控制，但人们喜欢说这是库贝的拥抱。
It obviously means kube control, but
people like to say that is kube cuddle.
因此，您可以单击此处以获取有关如何在您的操作系统中进行安装的指示信息。
So you can click here for instructions on
how to install in your operating system.
对于 Mac OS ，您可以在此处执行 curl 命令。
For Mac OS, you can just do
this curl command right here.
然后你把它变成可执行的，然后把它移到你的道路上。
And then you make it executable, and
then you move it into your path.
所以我已经安装了它，就这样做。
So I already have it installed but
again, just do this.
收到，它将是一个 curl 命令，所以我来这里说，哎呀。
Copy that, it will be a curl command, so
I'll come over here and say that, oops.
好吧那你先做这个然后做个 chmod
Okay, so you'd do that first,
then you'd do a chmod,
这使其可执行，因此您可以执行 chmod + x ，从而使其成为可执行文件。
this makes it executable, so you do
chmod + x, that makes it an executable.
然后你会把这个搬到你当地的垃圾桶里
And then you're gonna move this from
wherever that is into your local bin, or
就会在你的路上了
somewhere that's gonna be in your path.
所以在某个时候，你应该可以说 kubectl --版本。
So at some point, you should be
able to say kubectl --version.
还是只是版本?
Or is it just version?
好了好了
There you go.
这就是我现在要做的
So that's what I'm running right now.
好的
Okay, and
我在这里再次表示，您可以在使用 Docker Desktop之间作出选择。
again here I say that you can make
a choice between using Docker Desktop.
如果你在麦克的工作一切都很好我就建议
If you're on a Mac, and everything's
working fine, then I would just suggest
使用 Docker Desktop ，因为它工作，已安装。
using Docker Desktop because it works,
it's already installed.
但如果你在 Linux 上，你必须使用 Minikubbe，
But if you're on Linux,
you have to use Minikube,
所以你得通过 Minikube 公司的安装程序
so you're gonna have to go through
the Minikube installation process.
我想我是通过 Brew 找到的如果我没记错的话
I think I got it through Brew,
if I remember it correctly.
所以我也有一个链接来安装它
Yep, so
I have a link there to install it as well.
在这里的 Minikubbe，请参阅此处以了解如何进行安装，
So here down in Minikube,
see here for how to install,
Mac OS正在安装 Minikuba
Mac OS, Installing Minikube,
您应该已经在运行虚拟化，因为我们一直在做 Docker。
you should have virtualization already
running, because we've been doing Docker.
这些东西都应该起作用所以这就是它的存在
All this stuff should work,
so yeah, this is what it is,
正在酝酿安装迷你库
brew install minikube right there.
现在，如果你在 Windows 上，你可能可以通过 PowerShell 来运行这些东西。
Now if you're on Windows, you probably can
get this stuff running via PowerShell.
我也不知道 PowerShell ，所以
Again, I just don't know PowerShell, so
这都是留给你的所以如果你俩都像我一样
that's left to you, so
if you have both installed like me,
您可以说 kubectl 配置使用上下文。
you can say, kubectl config use-context.
你可以通过说， minikube 或者你可以说 docker桌面。
And you can switch between them by saying,
minikube or you can say docker-desktop.
所以如果我说迷你库贝现在你可以看到了
So if I said minikube right now,
you can see now it says minikube and
我可以像那样回到 Docker 桌面上。
I can go back to docker-desktop like that.
我又要和 Docker 桌面一起了
Again, I'm sticking with docker-desktop.
如果你用的是 Minikube ，你也得说 minikube 也开始了。
If you're using Minikube,
you have to say minikube start as well.
好了这一切都和库伯内特一起跑了
Okay, so that has gotten everything
running with Kubernetes.
它应该在你的电脑上执行
It should be executing now on your
computer, so let's go ahead and
进入这个，现在，正常情况下，
get into this, now, Normally,
你要做的就是把你的每一个服务定义为
what you would do is you would define
each one of your services with
他们自己的 Kubernetes YAML 文件定义，它需要这个，它需要这个。
their own Kubernetes YAML files that
define, it needs this, it needs that.
它需要很多不同的东西，它有很多的设置。
It needs a bunch of different stuff,
it's a lot of setup.
它非常了解各种不同的配置旋钮和
It's pretty involved understanding all the
various different configuration knobs and
像那样的东西
stuff like that.